<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>obsidian on Reorx’s Forge</title><link>https://reorx.com/tags/obsidian/</link><description>Recent content in obsidian on Reorx’s Forge</description><image><url>https://reorx.com/images/forge-v2-compat.svg</url><link>https://reorx.com/images/forge-v2-compat.svg</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reorx.com/tags/obsidian/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Switch open files quickly in Obsidian</title><link>https://reorx.com/blog/obsidian-switching-open-files-quickly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://reorx.com/blog/obsidian-switching-open-files-quickly/</guid><description>Imagine a quick switcher with open files at the top.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-problem">The problem</h2>
<p>since I use the “Sliding Panes” plugin, there’s always a bunch of files open in my Obsidian. Sometimes I switch to Obsidian with a very clear goal of opening a specific file, so I press Command+O and type in the file name to find it. Because I don’t want to check whether the file is open or not (rather say there’s no way to check open files quickly), I always press Command+Enter to open the file in a new pane. As this process repeats, some files will have redundant panes, the panes are bloated and the workspace ends up being a mess.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/darlal/obsidian-switcher-plus">Quick Switcher++</a> is a very helpful tool, it allows me to search for open editors by typing a special prefix (<code>edt</code> by default) in the quick switcher. But after using it a while, I still feel it’s not very intuitive, I want the “search any file and open it” action and “search for existing open file and activate it” to be combined into one thing to use.</p>
<h2 id="the-solution">The solution</h2>
<p>I forked Quicker Switcher ++ and added a new setting item called “Include open files”. When it’s enabled, the switcher modal shows all the open files at the top with a different color style. If the open file is chosen, make that pane active; Other suggestions behave the same as the original, opening the file in the active pane.</p>
<figure>
<video class="video-shortcode" preload="" controls>
  <source src="https://i.imgur.com/bGLcQKl.mp4" type="">
  There should have been a video here but your browser does not seem to support it.
</video>
</figure>

<p>I’ll test this new feature in my workflow for a while to see if it’s actually useful. Meanwhile, I’d love to hear from the Obsidian community. What do you think about it? Do you have a better idea for my problem? Feel free to leave a message to me.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>